A Guide to the Erwin Hoge Will Papers, 1918-1973
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Erwin Hoge Will Papers 1918-1973
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1974-004
1 container; 1.0 cu. ft.
Collection consists of materials regarding the professional, civic, and personal activities of Erwin Hoge Will.
Erwin Hoge Will
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
This collection was donated to the Special Collections in 1974.
Biographical Information
Born in Richmond, Virginia on January 8, 1900, Erwin Hoge Will graduated with a B.S. in Mechanical Engineering from Virginia Polytechnic Institute (Virginia Tech) in 1922. Will went on to serve a president and chief executive of the El Paso Electric Company as well as president and chairman of the board of directors for the Virginia Electric and Power Company. In addition, Will also held leadership positions with several civic improvement groups such as the Red Cross, the Rotary Club, the Chamber of Commerce, and the Masons.
Scope and Content
Collection contains materials concerning Erwin H. Will's professional achievements while working for the Virginia Electric and Power Company and the El Paso Electric Company; civic activities with groups such as the Red Cross, the Rotary Club, the Chamber of Commerce, and the Masons; as well as Virginia Tech memorabilia including dance cards, sheet music to "Tech Triumph," and 1922 commencement information.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically by subject matter
Contents List
- Biographical Information n.d. (Folder 1)
- Professional and Civic Activities 1928-32 (Folder 2)
- Professional and Civic Activities 1935-42 (Folder 3)
- Professional and Civic Activities 1942-47 (Folder 4)
- Professional and Civic Activities 1947-55 (Folder 5)
  - Includes information about Virginia Tech's World War II Memorial
- Professional and Civic Activities 1955-60 (Folder 6)
- Professional and Civic Activities 1960-65 (Folder 7)
- Professional and Civic Activities 1965-70 (Folder 8)
  - Includes a history of the Virginia Electric and Power Company written by Will
- Professional and Civic Activities 1970-73 (Folder 9)
- Queen of England, Visit to Virginia 1957 (Folder 10)
  - Includes an invitation to a luncheon with Queen Elizabeth II
- Travel 1957-71 (Folder 11)
  - Destinations include Europe, the Caribbean, Scandinavia, South America, and Africa
- Virginia Polytechnic Institute 1918-22 (Folder 12)
  - Photocopy of Will's 1922 diploma
  - 1922 commencement program
  - Basketball and football records
  - "Tech Triumph" sheet music
  - Dance cards
  - Two 1918 photographs of the cadet corps
- Virginia's 350th Anniversary Commission 1956 (Folder 13)
  - Includes information concerning the grave of Pocahontas (Rebecca Rolfe) at Gravesend, England